<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<HOPS>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Ahtanum</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>5.5</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Warmly aromatic and moderately bittering, Ahtanum is a hop of distinction. It is often likened to Cascade
      though without going that far, it makes more sense to say that Cascade may be an acceptable substitute. In
      comparison, Ahtanum is less bitter, its alpha acids are lower and its grapefruit essence is significantly more
      pronounced. It really is more akin to Willamette, with its notes of lemon and grapefruit.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.05</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Amarillo</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>8.9</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Amarillo offers solid bittering properties in the 9-11% Alpha Acid range and it packs one of the highest
      myrcene oil contents (60-70% of total oils) of any hop. This gives it a very sweet citrus flavor and aroma that is
      closer to oranges than grapefruit. The citrus character is backed by some light floral notes as well as melon and
      peaches.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.06</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Apollo</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>16.7</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Apollo’s abundance of alpha acids also come with a sharp, clean bittering profile with other highly desirable
      factors being great storage stability and disease tolerance. It is usually employed alongside aroma hops in order
      to achieve balance but when used as a late addition or dry hop itself, some grapefruit notes become evident.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.08</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Aramis</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>France</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>5.6</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It is sweet and spicy, citrusy and herby. The measure of its aroma and alpha characteristics make it
      appropriate for any and all kettle stages. It inherited Strisselspalt’s excellent aromas while providing a more
      plentiful and stable bittering quality.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.03</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Archer</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>UK</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>3.6</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Archer is an aroma hop that is typically used in only late boil additions, including dry hopping.
      Archer hops are said to have delicate and soft apricot, floral, lime and peach aromas. It combines classic
      assertive British aroma with a citrus twist.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.06</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Ariana</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>7.6</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It is juicy with dark fruits like blackcurrants and is backed by smooth oak, tobacco, and vanilla. There are
      also some bright elements of grapefruit when used in late additions.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.025</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Aurora</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Slovenia</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>10.2</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>With nearly twice the alpha acid content as Styrian Golding, another primary Slovenian hop, Aurora is spicy,
      herbal and moderately bittering. Descriptions and reviews of most beers employing Aurora hops describe them as
      pleasantly hoppy and velvety smooth.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.03</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Azacca</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>11.4</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Even with its high alpha acids, Azacca still works well as a dual-use hop, giving off a pleasant mix of
      tropical fruits kissed with citrus. On the palate it’s particularly spicy, with mango, pineapple and some pine and
      tangerine-esque qualities. It has also been likened in nature to some New Zealand-bred varieties.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.055</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Barbe Rouge</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>France</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>10.5</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Barbe Rouge is a bright and delicate aroma hop that offers ripe red fruit flavors of currant, strawberry, and
      raspberry. It also offers zesty citrus aromas of oranges and limes while some people describe a unique kumquat
      character.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.045</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Belma</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>8.9</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Belma has been tested as a dual-use hop and found to have an ambrosial mix of orange, melon, strawberry and
      pineapple with a slight hint of grapefruit.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.05</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Bobek</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Slovenia</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>3.8</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Also known as Styrian Bobek. Pleasant noble hop aromas of grass and pine, with hints of citrus.</NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.035</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Bramling Cross</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>UK</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>5.3</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>When used in large quantities the fruity element in Bramling Cross springs to life. This use exhibits complex
      fruity notes of lemon, blackcurrant and pear, particularly when used as a late addition. Some brewers have also
      recorded notes of blackberries and plums.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.035</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Bravo</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>11.3</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It’s bittering quality is considered smooth and in addition features light floral aromas and subtle flavors
      of orange and stone fruit making it highly desirable for use in many different ale styles.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.048</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Brewers Gold</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>UK</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>8.5</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>For brewer’s wishing to experiment though, Brewer’s Gold is still a good choice for late bittering with
      desirable notes of spice and blackcurrant. It is also nearly identical to sister selection Bullion.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.02</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Callista</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>4.1</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Callista has a mild alpha range but still manages to pack a fruity punch of stonefruits, ruby red grapefruit,
      and raspberries. Definitely shines in delicate styles like pilsners or in late additions for pale ales and IPAs.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.02</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Calypso</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>15.0</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Despite its aroma-focused origins, it boasts a high alpha acid percentage. In addition to this, Calypso
      features crisp, fruity aromas and flavors that exhibit elements of apple, pear and stone fruit brightened with
      hints of lime citrus. It is marvellously complex with an almost understated earthy, tea-like note.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.04</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Cascade (CH)</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Switzerland</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>4.5</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Cascade is bursting with zesty grapefruit flavor and aroma from the high levels
      of myrcene oil. It lends a pleasant and balanced bitter, but is ideally used in late hop additions to maximize
      that bright flavor and aroma. The bright citrus is backed by some soft floral and spice, which rounds out the
      profile.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.03</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Cascade (USA)</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>5.2</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Cascade is the hop that made hops famous. It single-handedly defined the American Pale Ale style. Cascade is
      bursting with zesty grapefruit flavor and aroma from the high levels of myrcene oil. It lends a pleasant and
      balanced bitter, but is ideally used in late hop additions to maximize that bright flavor and aroma. The bright
      citrus is backed by some soft floral and spice, which rounds out the profile.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.037</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Cascade (DE)</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>7.9</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Grown in the Hallertau, this Cascade is bursting with zesty grapefruit flavor and aroma from the high levels
      of myrcene oil. It lends a pleasant and balanced bitter, but is ideally used in late hop additions to maximize
      that bright flavor and aroma. The bright citrus is backed by some soft floral and spice, which rounds out the
      profile.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.025</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Cashmere</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Switzerland</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>7.3</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>A good dual-purpose hop, Cashmere showcases flavors lemon, lime and melon, exhibits a smooth bitterness and
      is mildly aromatic with a subtle herbal bouquet.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.06</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Celeia</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Slovenia</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>3.2</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Unfortunately, Celeia has not been well received by breweries to date and is not grown in large commercial
      quantities. It is described as slightly citrus and floral on the nose, pleasantly bitter and in symmetry with its
      aroma.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.04</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Centennial</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>7.9</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It is at times referred to as super Cascade because of its similar citric characteristic. Centennial is a
      much-celebrated hop in its versatility with its depth of bitterness and forward aroma.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.04</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Challenger</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>UK</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>8.0</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Challenger features decent bitterness and a floral aroma and as such are considered fine for bittering or for
      dry hopping. Its flavor is smooth with balanced floral characteristics, some citrus and a dash of spice.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.024</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Chinook</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>10.7</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Chinook hops are suitable for any stage of the boil. It features a pine-like, spicy bouquet with robust
      flavors of grapefruit.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.038</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Citra</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>12.5</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Citra, as the name implies, has a strong citrusy profile. This is largely credited to its very high myrcene
      content. It has an extraordinary flavor profile of grapefruit, lime and tropical fruits but despite its high
      alphas, brewers often warn against its use for bittering, which is considered by some to be harsh and undesirable.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.055</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Cluster</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>9.4</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>One of the oldest american hops. It is considered to have a clean, neutral and slightly floral flavor.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.04</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Columbus</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>15.5</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It features a punchy hoppiness and deep, pensive aroma with understated citrus notes—perfect as a dual use
      hop. Commonly used late in the boil and, when fresh, Columbus has a herbal flavor with a lemon citrus back note.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.03</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Comet</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>9.9</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Comet’s flavor profile rests heavily on a strong accent of grapefruit and dank resin flavors. It does feature
      solid bittering capabilities and traditionally brewers considered it best suited as a bittering agent for
      American-style lagers.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.06</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Crystal</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>2.3</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It’s woodsy, green, floral and fruity with herb and spice notes of cinnamon, nutmeg and black pepper.
      Extremely versatile, it’s even used for its notable aromatic qualities in IPAs and Bitters despite its low alpha
      acid content.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.05</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Dr. Rudi</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>New Zealand</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>10.5</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Considered a bittering hop, Dr Rudi is now widely regarded as dual-use and features a grassy, piney, citrus
      character. It is also well known for its clean and crisp bittering despite its high cohumulone content. Works well
      in single-hopped beers.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.055</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Ekuanot</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>12.5</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It has intense and unique fruity and citrus notes including melon, berry, citruslime, apple and papaya.
      Ekuanot also contains some spicy, green pepper note. This hop brand has high alpha acids content and high
      essential oil
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.05</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>El Dorado</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>13.4</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Bursting with juicy pineapple and tropical notes, this dual-purpose hop has been featured in many great beers
      since its release in 2010. Big Alpha Acids make this an effective and efficient bittering hop, but can be used in
      late additions to maximize the fresh, fruity aroma and flavor. When used in later additions, El Dorado brings
      bright tropical fruit flavors and aromas of pineapple, pear, watermelon, and stone fruit.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.05</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Elixir</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>France</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>5.5</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Elixir is a robust and complex hop that offers unique aromas of cognac, leather, and tobacco that are backed
      by sweet citrus fruits as well rose and lovage. Elixir is well suited for darker styles but can also be
      incorporated into fruit-forward styles or even spicy saisons.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.03</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Ella</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Australia</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>16.3</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Formally known as Stella. Due to its high level of oils, Ella can significantly change character depending on
      how it is utilized. When used in low quantities, it displays a spicy, floral character like star anise. When used
      in greater quantities or in dry hopping, it holds its own with any robust malt and conveys a decided tropical and
      grapefruit flavor.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.06</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Eureka</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>15.3</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Eureka is a fairly new variety with very strong bittering qualities and a complex and robust flavor and aroma
      profile. It is said to impart flavors of citrus, resin, tropical and dark fruit along with aromas of grapefruit
      rind, citrus and tangerine.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.055</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>First Gold</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>UK</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>7.6</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Versatile english hop with notes of tangerine, orange, cinnamon and mint.</NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.025</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Fuggles</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>UK</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>4.2</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Similar to a Styrian Golding, is noted for its distinct European aroma and has enjoyed a long, versatile run.
      Earthy aromas of grass and pine.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.028</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Galaxy</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Australia</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>14.2</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It has an amazing citrus, peach and passionfruit aroma, especially when used as a late addition. The flavor
      is often quite intense upon production but mellows as it matures.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.068</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Galena</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Australia</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>13.5</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Galena’s fruity flavor profile really kicks with clean and agreeable notes of citrus. Some brewers have noted
      its better when boiled in smaller quantities and that later additions bring forth stronger aromas of blackcurrant.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.06</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Glacier</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>5.0</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Glacier is a high yielding, dual-purpose hop characterized by low cohumulone levels, giving it a moderate and
      pleasant bitterness. Glacier’s aroma and flavor notes are herby, woody and citrusy.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.06</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>East Kent Goldings</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>UK</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>5.7</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Sometimes called the King of english hops. It has an amazing aroma profile with lavender, spice, honey and
      notes of thyme. Flavor-wise it is earthy and mildly bittering with a sweet, silky, honey-like character.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.026</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Green Bullet</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>New Zealand</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>11.7</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It has a special zing that has become New Zealand’s stock-in-trade. It’s a dual-use hop with high alpha
      acids, yet it has a smooth taste and aroma of raisins and fruits, possibly due to its high myrcene content.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.05</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Hallertau Blanc</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>8.4</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Hallertau Blanc’s flavor profile is said to be fruity, with wine-like qualities of gooseberry and grass,
      similar to that of Sauvignon Blanc. It also features a complex aroma profile with notes of cassis and elderflower
      in addition to grapes, grapefruit and lemongrass. Other notes detected in trials have been passionfruit, pineapple
      and gooseberry.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.025</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Hallertau Mittelfrüh</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>5.3</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Classic european noble hop. It features a lightly flowery and spicy aroma.</NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.019</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Hallertau Tradition</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>5.3</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Its oil profile contributes to a wonderfully earthy and grassy character atop a nose of nectar fruits. It is
      best used late in the boil, or for dry hopping. This utilization is preferential since its humulene content has
      been noted to dissipate rapidly when heated.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.018</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Herkules</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>17.6</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Herkules is a high alpha acid bittering hop, known to be spicy and floral, tangy and hoppy, with notes of
      melon, black pepper, with hints of pine.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.024</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Herkules (CH)</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Switzerland</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>16.9</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Herkules is a high alpha acid bittering hop, known to be spicy and floral, tangy and hoppy, with notes of
      melon, black pepper, with hints of pine.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.03</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Hersbrucker</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>3.3</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>With low alpha acids and low cohumulone, it exhibits a pleasant aroma with a balanced, fruity, spicy and
      floral character.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.02</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Horizon</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>11.5</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Considered dual-use it has high alpha acids, but also low cohumulone – a trait considered highly favorable
      when bittering. Its high myrcene and high farnesene content give it some great aroma and flavor notes too, both
      floral and citrusy.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.06</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Hüll Melon</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>8.9</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It has some interesting flavor characteristics not commonly associated with hops. It is noted to be intensely
      fruity with flavors and aromas of honeydew melon and strawberry.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.032</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Hüll Melon (CH)</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Switzerland</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>5.2</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It has some interesting flavor characteristics not commonly associated with hops. It is noted to be intensely
      fruity with flavors and aromas of honeydew melon and strawberry.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.035</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Idaho 7</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>13.3</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>This hop is ripe with zesty tangerine flavor that is reminiscent of marmalade. Its uniqueness shows up as a
      pleasant herbal character that melds with the citrus to come across like fine earl grey tea. It is a dual purpose
      hop capable of carrying a recipe, but it works best in conjunction with Citra or a bittering hop like Warrior.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.055</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Idaho Gem</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>12.6</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Idaho Gem is not just one-dimensionally fruity either as it is backed by some dank and floral elements that
      help it shine even outside of the hazy IPAs and fruit-forward styles where it is an obvious superstar.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.065</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Jester</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>UK</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>10.9</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Jester brings with it distinct flavors and aroma qualities quite different to that of tradition English hop
      varieties. These unique characteristics include forward and robust notes of tropical fruits, grapefruit and
      blackcurrant and even hints of Lychee. It is considered most useful as a mid to late addition but is also
      fantastic to dry hop with. Though not considered a particularly useful bittering hop, when used in this regard it
      imparts a mild, herbal resonance.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.06</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Junga</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>10.1</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>While some call Junga a dual-purpose hop, it is mainly used for bittering. Has limited potential for aroma or
      dry hopping use. However, if used for aroma, Junga hops give blackcurrant, grapefruit, and spice notes. Junga is
      comparable to German Magnum; not much taste but a great bittering hop.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.04</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Kazbek</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Czech Republic</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>5.6</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Kazbek hops brew up as a "Super Saaz" of sorts. It is bigger with aromas of citrus, sweet fruits, and
      berries, but still has that classic noble spice.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.038</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Kohatu</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>New Zealand</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>7.2</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Kohatu is not as fruity as Wai-iti, but with its intense aroma of tropical fruit and freshly crushed pine
      needles, it adds a wonderfully fresh character to beer. Even with a low alpha, when used as an early addition it
      features a pleasant, rounded bitterness.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.06</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Lemondrop</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>5.5</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Sometimes called Super-Cascade. Lemondrop hops offer strong citrus, floral, fruity, herbal, lemon, mint, adn
      light green tea aromas.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.05</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Liberty</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>4.4</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Similar to Hallertau Mittelfrüh or other european noble hops. Mild, resinous aromas with hints of citrus.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.08</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Lotus</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>15.1</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Lotus is described as having orange, vanilla, berry, and tropical fruits and was jokingly called orange
      creamsicle.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.06</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Magnum</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>15.1</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Used predominately as a base bittering hop, it is said to result in squeaky clean bitterness and subtle
      citrus-like flavors
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.023</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Magnum (CH)</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Switzerland</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>15.4</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Used predominately as a base bittering hop, it is said to result in squeaky clean bitterness and subtle
      citrus-like flavors
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.03</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Mandarina Bavaria</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>9.9</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It is useful for both flavor and aroma and imparts slightly sweet notes of tangerine and citrus, especially
      when used for dry hopping.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.02</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Mandarina Bavaria (CH)</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>10.9</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It is useful for both flavor and aroma and imparts slightly sweet notes of tangerine and citrus, especially
      when used for dry hopping.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.035</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Millenium</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>17.4</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>They work well as a bittering agent in American-style ales, Stouts and are considered mild in character with
      an ability to impart herbaceous notes and elements of resin.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.06</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Mistral</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>France</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>5.3</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Mistral offers a refreshing character of citrus fruits, floral, and sweet fruits.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.03</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Monroe</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>3.7</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Monroe hops are known for their bright, floral aroma, which is often described as having notes of
      honeysuckle, rose, and citrus. The flavor profile of Monroe hops is also distinctive, with a smooth bitterness and
      a hint of sweetness that is said to be reminiscent of ripe stone fruit.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.07</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Mosaic</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>11.6</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Mosaic hops feature complex but clean flavor characteristics and are known for their triple-use profile
      encompassing bittering, flavor and aroma. They have high alpha acids but low cohumulone which makes them
      pleasantly hoppy, carrying flavors of mango, pine, citrus and herbs and aromas of tropical and stone fruit.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.05</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Motueka</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>New Zealand</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>5.4</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It makes an excellent dual-use hop, carrying an exciting fruit aroma with refreshing notes of tropical fruit
      and citrus. It can be used at any point during the brewing process and works well in sweet, malty and fruity
      beers.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.055</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Mount Hood</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>3.2</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>An american hop trying to imitate european noble hops. It features a pleasant noble hop aroma and has been
      noted to impart somewhat of a flavor “punch” when freshly brewed – at least in comparison to true noble hops.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.04</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Nelson Sauvin</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>New Zealand</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>12.0</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Nelson Sauvin’s name is derived from the Sauvignon Blanc wine grape to which many agree has similar flavor
      and aroma characteristics. Nelson Sauvin’s oil profile is complex and fortunately works well as an aroma hop,
      flavor hop and also for bittering. Low cohumulone is responsible for its smooth bittering qualities. It boasts
      rich, fruity, gooseberry and white-wine flavors.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.07</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Nobility</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>4.8</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Primary aromas and flavors of citrus (lemon, orange), lemongrass, green tea, and herbaceous, with a mixture
      of floral and spice.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.065</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Northern Brewer</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>UK</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>9.1</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Dual-use hop with great smooth bitterness characteristics and typical minty and resinous aromas.</NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.016</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Nugget</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>12.3</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Nugget’s super alpha acid content, low beta and low cohumulone percentages give it an excellent bittering
      kick popular in IPAs, Imperials and other super hoppy brews. It’s high myrcene content also results in a green,
      herbal aroma.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.016</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Opal</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>9.0</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Opal hops feature a clean aroma and flavor profile of spice and citrus with a hint of sweetness.</NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.03</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Pacific Gem</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>New Zealand</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>11.1</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Despite its high alpha acids its high cohumulone content makes its use as a bittering hop problematic. It
      can, and is, used as an early addition but is more well known for its aroma and flavor. When utilized as a late
      addition it can bring a delicate aroma character to the resulting beer that is smooth and oak-like with notes of
      blackberry.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.1</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Pacific Jade</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>New Zealand</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>13.5</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It exhibits an interesting flavor profile of lemon citrus and cracked pepper. As an early addition it imparts
      a soft, rounded bitterness.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.055</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Pacifica</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>New Zealand</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>3.1</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Like Hallertauer Mittelfrüher, Pacifica is mostly known for its aromatic properties. It features moderately
      low cohumulone and higher carophyllene, which give it a spicy and decidedly floral aroma. Citrus notes are also
      evident and it is said to impart aromas of orange when used late in the boil.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.07</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Palisade</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>7.6</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It features complex floral, herbal and grassy aromas in addition to flavors of nectar fruits and citrus.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.06</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Perle</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>7.6</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Perle is said to have a pleasant aroma, elements of mint and pine with a hint of spice.</NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.02</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Perle (CH)</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Switzerland</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>4.3</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Perle is said to have a pleasant aroma, elements of mint and pine with a hint of spice.</NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.03</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Pilgrim</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>UK</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>9.0</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Considered round and full bodied with classic English-style bitterness, its complex flavor and aroma have
      been likened to grassy herbs, grapefruit citrus, berries and pears right through to spice, cedar and honey.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.04</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Pilot</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>UK</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>8.8</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>It’s oil balance makes it distinct from most other English hops. It is said to have excellent, clean and
      refreshing bittering qualities with spicy aromatics of lemon and marmalade.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.045</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Polaris</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>210.</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Commanding incredibly high alpha acids, Polaris features elements of spice, pine and intense mint alongside a
      strong but pleasant, fruity and floral aroma.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.04</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Saaz</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Czech Republic</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>3.7</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Saaz is one of the four original Noble hops and has a distinctive and classic aroma. It’s warm, herbal
      character stems from a high level of farnesene while its other oils are in fair balance. With such a low alpha
      acid percentage, Saaz is inarguably an aroma hop, however, when used as an early addition it is thought to add a
      delicate bitterness.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.025</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Saaz (CH)</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Czech Republic</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>2.3</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Saaz is one of the four original Noble hops and has a distinctive and classic aroma. It’s warm, herbal
      character stems from a high level of farnesene while its other oils are in fair balance. With such a low alpha
      acid percentage, Saaz is inarguably an aroma hop, however, when used as an early addition it is thought to add a
      delicate bitterness.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.035</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Sabro</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>13.9</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Sabro is an aroma hop that is notable for its complexity of fruity and citrus flavors. It imparts distinct
      tangerine, coconut, tropical fruit, and stone fruit aromas, with hints of cedar, mint, and cream.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.055</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Saphir</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>3.9</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Saphir features elements of spice and fruit amid refined citrus notes of tangerine.</NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.03</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Sequoia</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>10.3</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>The Sequoia Hop Blend has pronounced tropical fruit (mango, pineapple) with citrus and pine. Its sensory
      profile is a mix of tropical fruit and classic West Coast hop character.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.065</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Simcoe</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>12.9</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>With a high alpha percentage and low cohumulone, it makes a very nice foundational bittering hop. It is also
      noted though for its favorable aroma qualities. It has a pleasantly fruity, yet earthy herbal and piney aroma.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.045</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Sitiva</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>9.0</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Sitiva has ripe stone fruit, sweet floral, and soft peach flavors and aromas, as well as tropical fruit and
      lime character.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.04</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Solero</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>10.0</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>The Solero hop is a dual-purpose hop known to have strong fruit aromas and flavors including tropical and
      passion fruits along with mango.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.03</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Sorachi Ace</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Japan</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>10.6</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Sorachi Ace is considered excellent in several beer styles, particularly those desiring a distinct lemon
      citrus flavor. Some brewers have even reported flavors of orange, cilantro, dill, oak and coconut.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.05</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Southern Passion</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>South Africa</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>10.4</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>The aroma profile of the Southern Passion hop includes passion fruit, guava, red berries, floral, coconut,
      melon, calendula, and grapefruit.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.07</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Spalter Select</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>6.8</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>The result of a cross of Spalt and Hallertau Mittelfrüher, Spalter Select retains some of the finer
      characteristics of both these varieties and is considered a slightly spicier version of Spalt.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.02</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Spalter Select (CH)</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Switzerland</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>3.1</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>The result of a cross of Spalt and Hallertau Mittelfrüher, Spalter Select retains some of the finer
      characteristics of both these varieties and is considered a slightly spicier version of Spalt.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.03</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Sterling</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>10.7</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Sterling’s oil content is rather unusual with both very high farnesene and very low carophyllene. This
      creates a delicately spiced, citrusy aroma with both a floral and herbal punch.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.06</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Strata</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>14.2</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>The Strata hop has many layers of different fruit flavor, dried and fresh, anchored with a dried
      chili-cannabis-funk. Late hot side additions using Strata bring out layers of rounded-tropical plus bright-fresh
      fruit flavors; dry hopping yields more grapefruit and cannabis. Other descriptors include passion fruit,
      strawberry and dank.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.06</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Styrian Golding</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Slovenia</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>4.4</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Styrian Golding is a lovely aroma hop and exhibits resinous, earthy flavors that are perhaps considered
      slightly more refined than Fuggle. It has also been described as imparting subtle aromas of white pepper to a
      brew.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.028</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Styrian Wolf</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Slovenia</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>9.2</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>When brewed, expect intense fruity and floral notes. These include flavors of sweet tropical fruits and
      complex aromas of mango, elderflower and even a hint of violet.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.05</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Sultana</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>12.8</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Also called Denali, Sultana is rich in pineapple, citrus (often perceived as lemon), and pine flavors, though
      it can often come off as spicy as well.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.07</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Summit</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>15.1</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Summit boasts citric aromas of tangerine, grapefruit and orange along with an impressive alpha content giving
      it a wide spectrum of potential use.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.038</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Target</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>UK</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>9.0</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Target offers a robust citrus aroma that has been rediscovered by American craft brewers for big IPAs. Target
      is also noted for its aroma of fresh sage that makes it a fine complement to any West Coast IPA.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.025</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Taurus</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>15.4</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>German born Hallertau Taurus features an earthy, strong aroma with hints of chocolate and banana, spice and
      pepper and finishes with a zesty curry undertone.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.04</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Tettnanger</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>3.7</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Tettnanger has notably more farnesene content giving it a soft spiciness and a subtle, balanced, floral and
      herbal aroma. It is also great as a dual-use hop, and considered by many as being particularly well suited to
      European lagers and pilsners.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.025</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Tettnanger (CH)</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>2.7</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Tettnanger has notably more farnesene content giving it a soft spiciness and a subtle, balanced, floral and
      herbal aroma. It is also great as a dual-use hop, and considered by many as being particularly well suited to
      European lagers and pilsners.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.035</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Triumph</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>9.8</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Its noble genetics are definitely present, making it the perfect lager hop. But Triumph has also found a home
      in fruit forward ales and IPAs due to its bright aromas of orange, lime, and peach.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.055</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Vic Secret</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Australia</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>16.7</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Vic Secret features elements of tropical fruit, herbs and pine with clean notes of pineapple and
      passionfruit. It is also worth noting that late kettle additions impart a wonderful earthiness, but the fruitiness
      doesn’t come through.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.056</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Wai-iti</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>New Zealand</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>3.5</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>A truly modern triploid hop, Wai-iti brings forth a fresh splash of lime and stone fruit. Despite its low
      alpha content, low cohumulone and high farnesene would suggest a soft bitterness and potential suitability for
      single-hopped beers. When brewed as a mid-late addition, Wai-iti’s citrus aromas are said to take a back seat and
      make way for more of a stone-fruit presence.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.06</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Waimea</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>New Zealand</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>15.1</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Despite its incredibly high alphas, brewing characteristics of Waimea include some decidedly favorable flavor
      and aromas of fresh-crushed citrus and pine.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.05</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Wakatu</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>New Zealand</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>6.5</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Its nicely balanced oil profile gives it an understated floral aroma atop pungent fresh lime. Considered
      largely dual-use, it can be added at any stage of the boil right and dry hopped with success. It has also been
      noted for its impressive flavor stability.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Bittering / Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.07</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Willamette</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>6.4</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Americas answer to classic english hops. Willamette features complex spiciness characterized by both herbal,
      floral and fruity notes.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.045</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Yellow Sub</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>Germany</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>7.9</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>This composition turns a fine and excellent hop aroma into a sweet, fruity flamenco of apricot and orange,
      with a hint of blackberries. It's been described as "Amarillo on steroids".
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.05</COST>
  </HOP>
  <HOP>
    <NAME>Zappa</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <ORIGIN>USA</ORIGIN>
    <ALPHA>6.6</ALPHA>
    <USE>Boil</USE>
    <NOTES>Zappa hops have spicy aromas with intense notes of tropical fruit (mango, passion fruit), citrus, and pine.
      Additional descriptors include savory, mint, and Fruity Pebbles. This hop is unlike any other on the market today.
    </NOTES>
    <TYPE>Aroma</TYPE>
    <FORM>Pellet</FORM>
    <COST>0.055</COST>
  </HOP>
</HOPS>
