<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<YEASTS>
  <!-- Lallemand -->

  <YEAST>
    <NAME>Lallemand CBC-1</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>LalBrew</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>CBC-1</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>20</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>30</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>76</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>18</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>CBC-1 has been specifically selected for Cask and Bottle Conditioning applications due to its high resistance
      to alcohol and pressure. It has a neutral flavor profile and does not metabolize maltotriose, therefore the
      original character of the beer is preserved after refermentation. The yeast will settle and form a tight mat at
      the bottom of the bottle or cask.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.20</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>Lallemand Belgian Wit</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>LalBrew</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>Wit</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>17</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>25</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Low</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>79</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>12</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Wit is a relatively neutral wheat beer strain that can be used to produce a wide variety of wheat beer
      styles. It produces lower levels of esters and phenols compared to traditional hefeweizen strains. It provides a
      baseline profile of banana and spice aromas, but leaves space for the brewer to showcase other spice additions
      typical of Belgian-style beers.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.60</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>Lallemand Belle Saison</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>LalBrew</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>Saison</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>20</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>35</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Low</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>90</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>15</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Belle Saison is a Belgian-style ale yeast selected specially for its ability to create Saison-style beers. It
      is a diastaticus strain that allows the brewers to achieve the high attenuation characteristic of this classic
      style. Designed for warm-temperature fermentation true to traditional 'Farmhouse' production methods, beers brewed
      with Belle Saison are fruity, spicy and refreshing.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.50</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>Lallemand American West Coast</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>LalBrew</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>BRY-97</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>15</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>22</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>81</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>13</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>BRY-97 is an American West Coast-style ale yeast that was selected for its ability to produce clean
      fermentations for high quality ales. It is a neutral and highly attenuating strain with a high flocculation
      ability that can be used to make a wide variety of American-style beers.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.50</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>Lallemand Lager</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Lager</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>LalBrew</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>Diamond</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>10</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>15</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>80</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>13</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Diamond is a true lager strain. It delivers excellent fermentation performance, and has the ability to
      produce clean, authentic lagers.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.20</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>Lallemand Hybrid Saison-Style</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>LalBrew</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>Farmhouse</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>22</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>30</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Low</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>82</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>13</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Farmhouse is a non-diastatic hybrid that has been selected to make saison-style and farmhouse style beers. It
      was selected using the most advanced breeding techniques. The research team used classical and non-GMO methods to
      remove the STA1 gene, responsible for the diastatic activity of Saison yeasts. Care was taken to retain normal
      brewing sugar utilization to produce dry saisons.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.70</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>Lallemand Kölsch-Style</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>LalBrew</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>Köln</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>15</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>25</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Medium</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>81</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>9</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Köln is ideal for brewing traditional Kölsch-style beers and other neutral ales. The neutral character of
      this strain accentuates delicate hop aromas while imparting subtle fruity esters. Colder fermentations will be
      more neutral in character, while warmer fermentations will have more fruit-forward ester profile.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.50</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>Lallemand American East Coast</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>LalBrew</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>New England</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>25</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Medium</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>81</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>9</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>New England is an ale strain selected specifically for its ability to produce a unique fruit forward ester
      profile desired in East Coast styles of beer. A typical fermentation will produce tropical and fruity esters,
      notably stone fruits like peach. New England exhibits medium to high attenuation with medium
      flocculation, making it a perfect choice for East Coast style ales.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>5.20</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>Lallemand English-Style</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>LalBrew</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>London</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>22</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Low</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>69</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>12</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>London is a true English ale strain selected for its ability to produce authentic, traditional UK beer
      styles. Fermentation performance is fast and consistent producing moderate esters and lower attenuation due to an
      inability to metabolize maltotriose. A more subdued yeast character allows the flavors and aromas of malt and hops
      to shine through. London may also be used in the production of Ciders.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.20</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>Lallemand German Wheat</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>LalBrew</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>Munich Classic</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>17</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>25</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Low</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>80</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>12</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Munich Classic is a Bavarian wheat beer strain. It imparts the spicy and fruity aroma profile typical of
      German wheat beer styles. It produces higher levels of esters and phenols. It has robust and consistent
      performance making it a great choice for a variety of traditional wheat beer styles.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.20</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>Lallemand Nottingham</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>LalBrew</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>Nottingham</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>10</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>25</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>82</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>14</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Nottingham is an English-style ale yeast selected for its high performance and versatility. Neutral
      flavor and consistent performance across diverse fermentation conditions make it and ideal house
      strain for producing a wide variety of beer styles. It is a stress tolerant making it a good choice for high
      gravity, sours, re-starting stuck fermentations and other challenging fermentation conditions.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.50</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>Lallemand Verdant IPA</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>LalBrew</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>Verdant IPA</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>25</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Medium</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>80</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>12</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Verdant IPA was specially selected in collaboration with Verdant Brewing Co. (UK) for its ability to produce
      a variety of hop-forward and malty beers. Prominent notes of apricot and undertones of tropical fruit and citrus
      merge seamlessly with hop aromas. With medium-high attenuation, it leaves a soft and balanced malt profile with
      slightly more body than a typical American IPA yeast strain.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.70</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>Lallemand Kveik Yeast</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>LalBrew</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>Voss</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>25</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>40</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Very High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>80</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>12</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Kveik is a Norwegian word meaning yeast. In the Norwegian farmhouse tradition, kveik was preserved by drying
      and passed from generation to generation. Very fast fermentations are achieved within the optimal temperature
      range with full attenuation typically achieved within 2-3 days. The flavor profile is consistent across the entire
      temperature range: neutral with subtle fruity notes of orange and citrus.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.95</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>Lallemand Windsor</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>LalBrew</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>Windsor</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>15</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>25</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Low</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>68</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>12</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Windsor is a true English ale strain that produces a balanced fruity aroma with lower attenuation due to an
      inability to metabolize maltotriose. Beers created with it are usually described as full-bodied, fruity English
      ales. Windsor is a consistent and robust strain that produces moderate levels of alcohol and the balanced flavor
      and aroma characteristics of the best traditional English ales.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.50</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>Lallemand NovaLager</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>LalBrew</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>NovaLager</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>10</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>20</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Medium</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>81</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>13</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>LalBrew NovaLager is a true bottom-fermenting Saccharomyces pastorianus hybrid from the novel Group III
      lineage that has been selected to produce clean lager beers with distinct flavor characteristics and superior
      fermentation performance. LalBrew NovaLager is a robust lager strain with ideal characteristics for lager beer
      production including fast fermentations and high attenuation. The distinct flavor profile is very clean, slight
      esters over a wide temperature range. This strain is a low diacetyl producer and utilizes patented technology
      that inhibits the production of hydrogen sulfide off-flavors, therefore reducing the maturation time associated
      with lager beer production.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>6.20</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>WildBrew Philly Sour</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>LalBrew</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>Philly Sour</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>20</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>30</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>78</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>9</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Philly Sour produces moderate amounts of lactic acid in addition to ethanol in one simple fermentation step.
      This first yeast in the WildBrew series is a great choice for innovative, sessionable sour beers with refreshing
      acidity and notes of stone fruit.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.95</COST>
  </YEAST>

  <!-- Fermentis -->

  <YEAST>
    <NAME>SafAle BE-134</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>BE-134</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>26</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Low</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>91</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>11</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>SafAle BE-134 is a very powerful beer yeast with regards to flavor production. It produces several flavor
      active components, such as as fruity esters and phenolic / spicy components, at high concentrations. It has a very
      good diacetyl reduction power. Character is dry, ideal for highly refreshing beers like Belgian-Saison style.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>3.20</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>SafAle BE-256</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>BE-256</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>26</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>84</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>11</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Active dry brewer’s yeast recommended to ferment a diversity of Belgian type beers such as abbey style known
      for its fruitiness and high alcohol content. It ferments very fast and reveals strong fermentation aromas. To
      maintain the aromatic profile at the end of the fermentation, we do recommend to crop this yeast as soon as
      possible after fermentation.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>3.50</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>SafAle K-97</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>K-97</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>26</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Low</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>82</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>11</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>German ale brewer’s yeast producing subtle fermentation character. Depending on the conditions tend to
      present floral and balanced fruity character. Ideal for delicate beers such as German Kolsch beers, Belgian Wits
      and some versions of Session Beers. Suitable for heavily hopped beers and has ability to form a large firm head
      when fermenting.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>2.80</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>SafAle S-04</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>S-04</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>26</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>77</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>11</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>English ale brewer’s yeast selected for its fast fermentation profile. Produces balanced fruity and floral
      notes. Due to its flocculation power, tends to produce beers with higher clarity. Ideal for a large range of
      American and English Ales – including highly hopped beers – and is specially adapted to cask-conditioned and beers
      fermented in cylindro-conical tanks.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>2.70</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>SafAle S-33</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>S-33</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>26</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Medium</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>70</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>11</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Fruity driven strain, gives a high mouthfeel and body to the beer. Ideal for Belgian Ales (Blond, Dubbel,
      Tripel, Quadrupel Styles) and strong English ales (ex. Imperial Stouts). It is also ideal for New England IPAs.
      Yeast with a medium sedimentation: forms no clumps but a powdery haze when resuspended in the beer.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>2.20</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>SafAle T-58</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>T-58</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>26</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Medium</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>75</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>11</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Specialty brewer’s yeast selected for its strong fermentation character, intense fruity and phenolic flavors
      – especially banana, clove and peppery notes. Suitable for a great variety of wheat-base beers and fruity-spicy
      oriented styles. Yeast with a medium sedimentation: forms no clumps but a powdery haze when resuspended in the
      beer.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>2.20</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>SafAle US-05</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>US-05</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>26</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Medium</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>80</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>11</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>American ale brewer’s yeast producing neutral and well-balanced ales, clean and crispy. Forms a firm foam
      head and presents a very good ability to stay in suspension during fermentation. Ideal for American beer types and
      highly hopped beers.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>2.85</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>SafAle WB-06</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>WB-06</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>26</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Low</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>88</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>11</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Brewer’s yeast providing fruity and phenolic character, varying with the fermentation conditions. Produces
      well-attenuated beers and it is ideal for wheat base beers, such as Belgian and German Styles (Ex. Wit Beers and
      Weizen Beers). Produces typical phenolic notes of wheat beers. Allows to brew beer with a high drinkability
      profile and presents a very good ability to suspend during fermentation.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>3.30</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>SafBrew BR-8</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>BR-8</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>15</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>25</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Low</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>88</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>11</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>It offers all the flavor benefits of ‘wild’ Brett yeast, but with more control and reliability, eliminating
      the risk of over-carbonation and gushing after bottling. Selected specifically for secondary fermentation in
      bottles or casks, BR-8 produces phenolic compounds that create a distinctive finishing touch which evolves over
      time as the beer is aged, with funkier notes (barnyard, horse, leather…) nicely balanced by refreshing, fruity
      notes.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>13.50</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>SafBrew LA-01</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>LA-01</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>15</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>25</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Medium</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>15</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>5</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>LA-01, is a Saccharomyces cerevisiae var. chevalieri that has been specifically selected for the production
      of low and/or non-alcoholic beverages (0.5ABV). This yeast does not assimilate maltose and maltotriose but
      assimilates simple sugars (glucose, fructose and sucrose) and is characterized by a subtle aroma profile.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.50</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>SafLager S-189</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Lager</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>S-189</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>12</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>18</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>82</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>10</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Originating from the Hürlimann brewery in Switzerland. This lager yeast strain’s profile allows to brew
      fairly neutral flavor beers with a high drinkability. Depending on the conditions, it tends to present noticeable
      herbal and floral notes to lager beers.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.55</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>SafLager S-23</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Lager</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>S-23</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>12</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>18</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>82</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>10</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Bottom fermenting brewer’s yeast originating from Berlin in Germany. SafLager S-23 recommended for the
      production of fruitier and more estery lagers. Its profile gives beers with a good length on the palate.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>3.80</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>SafLager W-34/70</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Lager</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>W-34/70</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>12</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>18</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>82</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>10</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>This famous brewer’s yeast strain from Weihenstephan in Germany is used world-wide within the brewing
      industry. W-34/70 allows the brewing of beers with a good balance of floral and fruity aromas and gives
      clean flavors and high drinkable beers.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.10</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>SafAle BW-20</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Fermentis</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>BW-20</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>26</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Medium</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>80</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>10</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Selected in Flanders, the northern part of Belgium, Fermentis SafAle BW-20 is a medium attenuative yeast that
      has been specifically selected for the production of Belgian Wheat beers, also called Witbiers. While producing
      esters (banana notes) and phenols (4-VG) which are important components for Witbiers, SafAle BW-20 is less
      aromatic than other Fermentis wheat yeasts on this aspect.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.10</COST>
  </YEAST>

  <!-- Mangrove Jack's -->

  <YEAST>
    <NAME>MJ Mead</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Wine</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Mangrove Jack's</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>M05</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>15</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>30</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>98</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>18</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>A high ester-producing strain conferring fresh, floral esters, especially when
      fermented cool. This yeast has high alcohol tolerance and ferments well over
      a wide temperature range. When using honey you will need a yeast nutrient with this yeast for
      healthy fermentation.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>2.20</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>MJ Bavarian Lager</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Lager</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Mangrove Jack's</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>M76</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>8</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>14</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Medium</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>78</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>8</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>A bottom-fermenting yeast suitable for most lager styles. Promotes less sulphur
      production than other lager strains, as well as a fuller, more rounded malt character
      with well-promoted hop flavours.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>3.60</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>MJ Bavarian Wheat</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Mangrove Jack's</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>M20</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>30</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Low</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>74</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>7.5</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>A top-fermenting wheat beer yeast which imparts banana and clove esters
      balanced with spiced aromas. This yeast produces a silky mouthfeel and rich body.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>2.60</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>MJ Belgian Abbey</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Mangrove Jack's</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>M47</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>25</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>75</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>8</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Moderately alcohol tolerant with fewer phenols than Belgian Ale, this yeast is
      exceptionally fruity with hugely complex esters and is highly flocculant.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>2.60</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>MJ Belgian Ale</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Mangrove Jack's</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>M41</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>28</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Medium</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>86</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>12</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Spicy and phenolic, this yeast emulates the intensity and complexity of some of
      the best monastic breweries in Belgium. High attenuation and alcohol tolerance
      allows you to brew a huge range of Belgian beers.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>3.80</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>MJ Belgian Tripel</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Mangrove Jack's</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>M31</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>28</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Medium</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>86</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>10</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>Provides a fantastic complex marriage of spice, fruity esters, phenolics and alcohol.
      It is also very attenuative with a high alcohol tolerance making it perfect for a
      range of Belgian styles.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.00</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>MJ Belgian Wit</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Mangrove Jack's</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>M21</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>25</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Low</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>73</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>8</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>A traditional, top-fermenting yeast that has a good balance between fruity esters,
      and warming spice phenolics. The yeast will leave some sweetness, and will drop
      bright if left long enough.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>2.50</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>MJ Californian Lager</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Lager</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Mangrove Jack's</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>M54</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>20</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>80</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>9</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>A unique lager yeast that has the ability to ferment at ale temperatures without the
      associated off flavours. Extended lagering periods are also not required.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.30</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>MJ Empire Ale</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Mangrove Jack's</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>M15</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>22</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>73</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>8</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>A top-fermenting ale yeast suitable for a variety of full bodied ales, with
      exceptional depth. Ferments with full, rich, dark fruit flavours.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.30</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>MJ French Saison</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Mangrove Jack's</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>M29</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>26</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>32</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Medium</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>90</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>14</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>French Saison yeast is an exceptional, highly attenuative top-fermenting ale
      yeast, creating distinctive beers with spicy, fruity and peppery notes. Ideal for
      fermentation of farmhouse style beer.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.00</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>MJ Hophead Ale</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Mangrove Jack's</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>M66</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>22</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>78</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>10</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>A yeast and enzyme blend that enhances aromatics and esters, perfect for New
      England, hazy and fruit forward IPAs. Select enzymes improve aroma and flavour
      from late hop and fruit additions.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.20</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>MJ Kveik</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Mangrove Jack's</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>M12</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>20</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>40</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Very High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>79</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>12</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>A top fermenting yeast, Voss Kveik offers fast fermentation at very high temperatures
      whilst retaining a neutral flavour character with subtle citrus fruit notes.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.10</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>MJ Liberty Bell</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Mangrove Jack's</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>M36</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>23</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>76</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>9</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>A top-fermenting ale yeast suitable for a wide variety of hoppy and distinctive
      style beers. This strain produces light, delicate fruity esters and helps develop
      malt character.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>3.30</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>MJ New World Strong Ale</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Mangrove Jack's</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>M42</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>16</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>22</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Very High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>80</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>12</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>A top-fermenting ale strain suitable for many types of ales of all strengths.
      Ferments with a neutral yeast aroma to ensure the full character of the malts and
      hops are prominent in each beer.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>3.30</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>MJ US West Coast</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Mangrove Jack's</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>M44</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>18</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>23</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>High</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>81</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>11</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>A top-fermenting ale strain suitable for American style ales. This yeast produces
      an exceptionally clean flavour, ideal for when you want the hop character to really
      punch through.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>3.10</COST>
  </YEAST>
  <YEAST>
    <NAME>MJ Versa Lager</NAME>
    <VERSION>1</VERSION>
    <TYPE>Ale</TYPE>
    <FORM>Dry</FORM>
    <LABORATORY>Mangrove Jack's</LABORATORY>
    <PRODUCT_ID>M24</PRODUCT_ID>
    <MIN_TEMPERATURE>10</MIN_TEMPERATURE>
    <MAX_TEMPERATURE>20</MAX_TEMPERATURE>
    <FLOCCULATION>Medium</FLOCCULATION>
    <ATTENUATION>81</ATTENUATION>
    <MAX_ABV>13</MAX_ABV>
    <NOTES>This rebranded LalBrew NovaLager is a bottom-fermenting yeast capable of fermenting under either cold or warm
      conditions. Produces clean lagers with low sulfur and low diacetyl, allowing for fast fermentation and reduced
      maturation times.
    </NOTES>
    <COST>4.95</COST>
  </YEAST>
</YEASTS>
